<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Installation Help</title>
    </properties>

    <meta name="keyword" content="maven, mvn, proxy, deployment"/>

    <body>
        <section name="Basic Information">
            <p>
                Artifactory system requirements:
                <ol>
                    <li>A valid
                        <b>JDK 1.6</b>
                        installed on the server.
                    </li>
                    <li>At least 400m of Java heap size, for good management of the binary files.</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            <p>
                <i>
                    The downloadable artifactory zip install file contains an embedded Jetty container
                    with a with default Artifactory configuration for ultra easy startup.
                    After unzipping it, run the appropriate Windows or Linux script under the bin
                    directory.
                </i>
            </p>
            <p>The bin folder also contains an install script for making artifactory
                a Linux service using chkconfig (RedHat and Suse).
            </p>
            <p>You can read the
                <a href="configuration.html">Configuration</a>
                page for a description of artifactory folders.
            </p>
            <p>After installation the default admin user is username=admin and password=password</p>
        </section>
        <section name="Windows">
            <p>
                The file "artifactory.bat" under the bin folder, will look for java and run
                the Main class with the option "-version:1.6", for ensuring 1.6 validity.
            </p>
            <p>ATTENTION: The above java option may not work with JVMs other than Sun's, please
                modify it accordingly.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Linux">
            <p>The main dependency needed before running artifactory is to have a valid JDK 1.6 on the machine.
                Before running scripts directly the JAVA_HOME should be set to a JDK 1.6.
            </p>
            <p>The best to check the validity of your environment is to run "artifactoryctl check"
                under the bin folder. This script is a modification of jetty init script and is quite well
                documented.
            </p>
            <p>You can run artifactory with "artifactory.sh" directly to see its behavior.
                The console will be locked on artifactory process and you can stop it clean with CTRL+C.
            </p>
            <p>You can also try run directly "artifactoryctl check|start|stop" to run directly
                artifactory as a daemon process using the environment variable of the shell you are in.
            </p>
            <p>There is also under bin a script called "install.sh" that will run a bunch of
                unix commands to setup artifactory correctly as a Linux service.
            </p>
            <p>The install script is documented and you should look at it before running it.
                Anyway, here are the notes and informations about what this script is doing:
            </p>
            <table>
                <tr>
                    <td>NOTE</td>
                    <td>This script should be run as root</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>NOTE</td>
                    <td>It uses chkconfig which is part of RedHat and Suse but not debian (as I know it)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>User creation</td>
                    <td>It creates a user named "jetty" (JETTY_USER) by default.
                        The install script accept the username as it first and only parameter.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>etc config</td>
                    <td>It creates the folder /etc/artifactory copy the configuration files there and
                        creates a soft link in $ARTIFACTORY_HOME/etc
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>etc default</td>
                    <td>It creates the file /etc/artifactory/default that contains the main environment
                        variables needed for artifactory to run: JAVA_HOME, JETTY_USER, ARTIFACTORY_HOME, JAVA_OPTIONS,
                        ...
                        <br/>
                        The /etc/artifactory/default is included at the beginning of artifactoryctl and so can include
                        whatever you wish.
                        <br/>
                        <b>Becareful: The default max memory is 1G</b>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>init.d</td>
                    <td>It copy the file artifactoryctl to /etc/init.d/artifactory</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Logs folder</td>
                    <td>It creates /var/log/artifactory make it writable for the user JETTY_USER
                        and creates a soft link $ARTIFACTORY_HOME/logs.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Backup folder</td>
                    <td>This script will create the folder ARTIFACTORY/backup directly, so you
                        need to create a link if you want this folder to be somewhere else
                        (like /var/backup/artifactory for example).
                        The script make $ARTIFACTORY_HOME/backup it writable for the user JETTY_USER.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Repos folder</td>
                    <td>This script will create the folder ARTIFACTORY/repos directly, so you
                        need to create a link if you want this folder to be somewhere else.
                        The script will make it writable for the user JETTY_USER.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>chkconfig call</td>
                    <td>The script call add, list (you can see the output), then activate (on), the artifactory
                        service
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
            <p>After running the script successfully you can test the installation by running:
                "service artifactory check" or "/etc/init.d/artifactory check"
            </p>
            <p>And if everything OK start artifactory with:
                "service artifactory start" or "/etc/init.d/artifactory start"
            </p>
            <p>And then check the log with:
                "tail -f $ARTIFACTORY_HOME/logs/consoleout.log"
            </p>
            <p>Enjoy...</p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>