<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Configuration Help</title>
    </properties>

    <meta name="keyword" content="maven, mvn, proxy, deployment"/>

    <body>
        <section name="Configuration Files">
            <p>
                All artifactory configuration files should be located under etc of the ARTIFACTORY_HOME.
                On Linux it is usually a soft link to /etc/artifactory.
                This folder should contain the following files:</p>
            <table>
                <tr><td>File Name</td> <td>Description</td> </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>jetty.xml</td>
                    <td>The standard jetty configuration file,
                    that can be tuned by adding the AJP connector, for example.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>log4j.properties</td>
                    <td>The standard log4j configuration file,
                    that can (should ;-) be tuned for changing default level from INFO to ERROR.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>artifactory.config.xml</td>
                    <td>The artifactory configuration file, that will be read only when artifactory starts,
                        and that contains the definitions of all artifactory local and remote repositories.
                        This XML files is based on well documentated XML Schema availiable
                        <a href="/xsd/artifactory.xsd">here</a>
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </section>
        <section name="Artifactory folders">
            <p>Under the Artifactory homeyou willfind the following subfolders:</p>
            <table>
                <tr><td>Folder Name</td> <td>Description</td> </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>bin</td>
                    <td>All scripts for running and installing artifactory</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>lib</td>
                    <td>Jetty jars and any other jars you wish to add to jetty classpath</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>webapps</td>
                    <td>Standard jetty folder for war files that will deployed by jetty.
                        By default the jetty.xml provided deploys only artifactory.war under this folder.
                        There is no auto-deploy.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>artifactory.jar</td>
                    <td>A simple java jar containing only the Main startup class.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>etc</td>
                    <td>The folder with all artifactory configuration files for jetty,
                        log4j and of course artifactory itself.
                        Under Linux it is usually a link to /etc/artifactory and
                        contains a file "default" for the service variables.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>logs</td>
                    <td>The folder where all logs files will go. By default the jetty
                        console will go to logs/consoleout.log. This folder should exists and be writable
                        when starting artifactory since log4j cannot create folder dynamically.
                        Under Linux it is usually a link to /var/log/artifactory.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>repos</td>
                    <td>The folder where artifactory own DB and the repositories databases will be created.
                        Theses databases are Derby DB files. Artifactory will create these DB files based
                        on its configuration and so the folder may not exists when artifactory starts.
                        Under Linux it is usual to link this folder to /var/data/artifactory or /srv/artifactory/repos.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>backup</td>
                    <td>The folder where artifactory scheduled backup will be done.
                        The backups are flat export of all files in all local repositories.
                        Under Linux it is usual to link this folder to /var/backup/artifactory.
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>