<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Security Configuration</title>
    </properties>

    <meta name="keyword"
          content="artifactory, security, maven, proxy, enterprise, repository, corporate, maven 2,
          maven2, mvn, manager, deployment"/>

    <body>
        <section name="Maven Authentication">
            <p>
                For authenticating via Maven, you need to have similar configuration in your
                settings.xml:
                <source><![CDATA[
<servers>
    <server>
        <id>repository-name-used-in-the-pom-to-refer-to-artifactory</id>
        <username>myUsername</username>
        <password>myPassword</password>
    </server>
</servers>]]></source>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Repository and Path Permissions">
            <span>
                <p>
                    Since version 1.2.1 of Artifactory, a new improved security model is used.
                    The new model allows for setting permissions on targets that are a combination of a
                    repository and a path prefix inside a repository.
                </p>
            </span>

            <span>
                <img src="images/permissions.jpg"/>
            </span>
            <span>
                <p>
                    The following permission-targets samples should make this concept clearer:
                    <br/>
                    <table>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <b>&lt;repo&gt;:&lt;path&gt;</b>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <b>Description</b>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>lib-releases:org/apache</td>
                            <td>refers to any artifact deployed under the "org/apache" path (including sub paths) inside the "lib-releases" repository</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>ANY:org/apache</td>
                            <td>refers to any artifact deployed under the "org/apache" path (including sub paths) inside any repository</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>plugin-snapshots:ANY</td>
                            <td>refers to any artifact deployed under any path inside the "plugin-snapshots" repository</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>ANY:ANY</td>
                            <td>refers to any artifact deployed under any path inside any repository (this is useful for allowing global read permission for authenticated users, where anonymous download is not enabled)</td>
                        </tr>
                    </table>
                </p>
                <p>
                    The roles of admins, deployers and readers are still applicable for this new type of
                    permission-targets.
                    <br/>
                    The admin role is fully functional for one is an admin of.
                </p>
                <p>
                    For each permission-target you can assign users to 3 types of roles:
                    <ol>
                        <li>
                            <b>Deployers</b>
                            - can deploy/remove (undeploy) artifacts.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <b>Viewers</b>
                            - can download artifacts (simple browsing is still enabled for
                            anyone), unless a repository has the
                            <code>&lt;anonDownloadsAllowed&gt;</code>
                            flag set to true (the default), then anyone can download regardless of
                            whether or not he is a viewer.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <b>Admins</b>
                            - can set permissions to other users inside the permission-target.
                        </li>
                    </ol>
                </p>
            </span>

        </section>
        <section name="Global Admins">
            <p>
                A defined user can either be a simple user or an "admin" user (similar to a root
                user). When a user is defined as an admin he automatically has all
                3 roles for any repository or path.
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>