<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Setting up security</title>
    </properties>

    <meta name="keyword"
          content="artifactory, security, maven, proxy, enterprise, repository, corporate, maven 2,
          maven2, mvn, manager, deployment"/>

    <body>
        <section name="Groups">
            <p>
                You can create groups, each group useing a groupId prefix for its name.
                <br/>
                This groupId translates to the path prefix of stored artifacts, and is used to
                determine the effective permissions when referring to a repository path.
            </p>
            <p>
                For each group you can assign users to 3 types of roles:
                <ol>
                    <li>
                        <b>Deployers</b>
                        - can deploy/remove (undeploy) artifacts.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>Viewers</b>
                        - can download artifacts (simple browsing is still enabled for
                        anyone), unless a repository has the
                        <code>&lt;anonDownloadsAllowed&gt;</code>
                        flag set to true (the default), then anyone can download regardless of
                        whether or not he is a viewer of a group of an artifact in the repository.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>Admins</b>
                        - currently unimplemented (will be used to allow management
                        of users within a group in the next version).
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Users">
            <p>
                A defined user can either be a simple user or an "admin" user (similar to a root
                user). When a user is defined as an admin he automatically has all
                3 roles for any group (including undefined groups).
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Sample Use Case">
            <p>
                Suppose you need to deploy an artifact with a groupId of "org.apache.maven".
                You will need to create a group with any of the following names (prefixes):
                "org", "org.apache" or "org.apache.maven".
                <br/>
                Then you assign appropriate users as deployers of this group.
            </p>
            <p>
                For authenticating via Maven, you need to have similar configuration in your
                settings.xml:
                <source><![CDATA[
<servers>
    <server>
        <id>repository-name-used-in-the-pom-to-refer-to-artifactory</id>
        <username>myUsername</username>
        <password>myPassword</password>
    </server>
</servers>]]></source>
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>